Nathan Mackenzie

75 Pork Point Road, Bowdoinham ME, 04008 (207) 841-5939 | nathan.mackenzie@maine.edu

A feed-forward neural network written in C++. Uses a sigmoidal activation function and a back

Capstone design project for research purposes. Makes use of two lead screw linear actuators to

apply a normal and shear force to prototype force sensors. Stepper motors controlled by an

A MATLAB program which preforms an analysis on a closed Brayton cycle power plant to help

propagation teaching method to train the network to a provided training set.

Education

B.S. Mechanical Engineering University of Maine, Orono GPA: 3.3

Notable Projects

2-Axis Force Test-Bench

Power Plant Analysis

Handwriting AI

Arduino Mega.

2015 - Present

Skills

Java

- AWT, Swing, and JFX
- MVC design architecture
- · Familiarity with JUnit test suite

C/C++

- Bit Masking
- TCP/IP Sockets
- Multithreading

Visual Basic/.NET

• SerialPort interfacing with Arduino for

Linux/UNIX

- Bash
- Arch Linux kernel
- OpenBox/KDE

Aug 2018 - Present

Mechanical Assembly Intern

Work History

Lanco Intergrated, Westbrook Maine

• Follow engineering drawings to manufacture and assemble modules

• Write and manage blowmolding preventative maintenance schedules

Assist with production line modifications and trouble shooting

Modify engineering drawings and components as necessary

determine how to achieve maximum energy and cost efficiency

Assist Mechanical & Electrical Technicians as necessary

Git/Github

Javascript

- Bootstrap
- jQuery

HTML

Undergraduate Research Assistant

Manufacturing Engineer Intern

Nestlé Waters, Poland Spring

Jan 2016 - May 2016

May 2018 - Aug 2018

NASA HIAD Research, UMaine Advance Manufacturing Center

Research and implement production line improvements

- Assist in data collection of ballistics testing on inflatable inner tube materials
- Analyze woven fabric structures
- Construct graphical analysis of experimental data

CSS

SOL

References

Links

NateMackenzie.com

Available Upon Request